experian.co.uk 2017-12-26

# Privacy statement - Experian UK and Ireland

This privacy policy statement sets out the data processing practices carried out through your use of this web site by Experian Limited, its holding companies and subsidiaries (“the Group”).

If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices please [contact us](http://www.experian.co.uk/contact-us/index.html "Contact us page").

### Links

This privacy policy only covers Experian's web site at www.experian.co.uk. Additional web sites within the Group are governed by their respective privacy statements. We are not responsible for the data policies or procedures or the content of other linked web sites outside of the Group.

### Information collected

We collect personal information from visitors to this web site through the use of enquiry forms and every time you e-mail us your details. Other than this, we do not store or capture personal information but simply log your IP address (this is the technical standard which ensures messages get from one host to another and that the messages are understood) which is automatically recognised by the web server.

### Use of personal information

We process personal information collected via this web site for the purposes of: -

  * Identifying potential customers or subscribers.
  * Dealing with your requests and enquiries.
  * Carrying out customer and marketing research.
  * Providing you with information about products and services offered by Experian
  * Processing your application for employment at Experian, in which case, please see the section on Applying for a career at Experian below.

We do not sell personal information collected through this site or use your personal information for any other purposes than those stated above.

### Cookies

Cookies may be used by us to provide you with customised information from our web site. A cookie is an element of data that a web site can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our web site. Cookies may also allow us to make our web site more user friendly by, for example, allowing us to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it every time to visit our web site.

We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our web site. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. You do not have to accept cookies, and you should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, this will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. If you disable cookies from your browser you may not be able to access certain features of a particular web site.

For more information about our use of cookies please click here.

### Security

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information. All the data collected by us is stored on a secure server. The secure server software encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us.

### Disclosures

We will only disclose personal information to reputable companies and suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf, (which may include companies within the Group).

### Internet-based Transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing this web site and communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way.

### Applying for a career at Experian

**Security**

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information. All the data collected by us is stored on a secure server. The secure server software encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. For your part you should ensure that the credentials you use to access Experian systems are kept securely. Passwords should not be guessable. We strongly recommend that, as a minimum, passwords are a minimum of 8 characters long and contain a mix of upper and lower case characters and numbers. Passwords should be changed frequently, and they should never be written down or shared.

**Data protection statement**

Personal information about you which we obtain in the course of considering your suitability for employment will be stored and processed in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. The data will be processed in relation to your application to work for Experian or for the inclusion in your personal records if you become an Experian employee.

For the purposes of complying with the Data Protection Act, the personal information about you will be used by Experian Background Checking to discharge its duties as laid out in its contract with Experian, which specifically includes the passing on of personal information to Experian. This will not be disclosed for any other purpose without the express permission of the applicant.

In processing this information, Experian may use the services of third parties, possibly based outside the UK or European Economic Area. However all third parties are thoroughly vetted by Experian and your information will only be used for the purposes of processing your application and considering your suitability for employment.

The information collected will be retained for profile matching purposes and put forward where appropriate to selected members of Experian HR and line managers when recruiting for future opportunities that match your profile.

The information collected will be retained for the purpose of screening you for employment with Experian and you understand that if offered the position, employment will be subject to satisfactory employer references and satisfactory results from any other background checks that may be required.

If employed by Experian, such checks may then be repeated periodically throughout your employment with the Company.

It is your responsibility to maintain and update your data held in this system, however Experian may from time to time request, via email, that you update your data. You have the right to access and update your data at any time by accessing this system. Data will not be kept for longer than is necessary and will be removed from our database at your request. If you wish Experian to delete your profile, please contact us.

It is your responsibility to ensure that the computer you are using for the processing of your data is adequately secured and protected against malicious software, such as trojans, computer viruses and worm programs. You are aware of the fact that without adequate security measures (e.g. secure web browser configuration, up-to-date antivirus software, personal firewall software, no usage of software from dubious sources) there is a risk that the data and passwords you use to protect access to your data, could be disclosed to unauthorized third parties.

**Verification of personal data**

I authorise Experian Background Checking or any agent thereof to carry out all necessary enquiries to verify the information I have submitted on this form or any other information which may be relevant to my application.

I also authorise Experian Background Checking to verify my identity either by me providing appropriate documentation as requested or by Experian Background Checking undertaking a search to check the details supplied against my particulars on any databases to which they have access

I authorise Experian Background Checking, or any agent thereof, to make enquiries of the school, college or university or other educational establishment where a qualification was gained

I authorise enquiries to be made of my financial and credit history where applicable. These checks will only use data that is held within Experian’s systems, by fraud prevention agencies or other appropriate third parties.

I understand that I will be required to produce documentation that is required by law to establish my right to work in the UK or EEA.

I understand that Experian may also require that a check is made on any criminal convictions I may have had in the past. I give consent to Disclosure Scotland to mail my disclosure certificate directly to Experian Background Checking and consent to Experian Background Checking opening and handling my disclosure certificate. I authorise Experian Background Checking to provide details of my disclosure report to Experian and to hold a copy of my disclosure until 6 weeks after the completion of my background check.

I understand that Experian Background Checking will endeavour to carry out all enquiries in a proper and sensitive way and I authorise them to speak to or otherwise communicate with me concerning any ambiguity or other reason, in order that such enquiries can fairly and diligently be carried out.

I understand that if any information gives cause for concern Experian will discuss the information with me and the possible impact on my employment.

I authorise Experian Background Checking to retain this information and to provide this to any other future employer with my consent.

Should our investigations identify fraud or the commission of any other criminal offence by you (on your part) when applying for, or during the course of your employment with us, we will record details of this on fraud prevention databases. This information may be accessed from the UK and other countries and used by law enforcement agencies and by us and other employers (and potential employers) to prevent fraud. If you want to receive details of those fraud prevention agencies write to us at Experian Ltd, PO Box 8000, Nottingham, NG80 7WF. You have a legal right to these details.

Please note that these checks will only be carried out if your application is successful. If your application is unsuccessful, no such checks will be carried out on you.

I understand that if I supply untrue information or wilfully mislead in any answers given then this may subsequently lead to any offer of employment being withdrawn, or where employment has already commenced, the termination of such employment.

**Declaration**

By registering on our careers site, you are deemed to consent to our processing personal data about you where necessary for the above purposes, including the processing of any sensitive personal data about you.

### Personal Data and your rights

If we collect any personal data from you, you have the right to receive information about the personal data we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee). The statutory fee is currently £10.00.

If at any time you no longer wish to receive any of our e-bulletins, newsletters or other information for which you have subscribed via this website, then please contact us so that we can remove your relevant details.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time. You should check this page regularly to see our most up to date policy. We will tell you about any changes to this Privacy policy by showing the date of the changes in the 'Last updated' section below. By using the website after the date we make any changes, you are agreeing to the changes.

**Last updated: July 2017**
